<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jen Sparks - Hobbies</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/hobbies.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-06-02T15:28:00-05:00</updated><subtitle>A personal playground</subtitle><entry><title>Pixelbook mCover Hard Shell Case Mod</title><link href="/pixelbook-mcover-hard-shell-case-mod.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-02T15:28:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-02T15:28:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-06-02:/pixelbook-mcover-hard-shell-case-mod.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I got my Pixelbook a while back, I've wanted a case that would work for both the laptop and tablet mode. Unfortunately, they really don't seem to exist. The closest I found was the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07D6DPD2N/ref=cm_sw_em_r_mt_dp_U_fKb9Cb3267RRT"&gt;mCover Hard Shell Case for 12.3" Google Pixelbook Chromebook&lt;/a&gt;, but even this wouldn't let …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I got my Pixelbook a while back, I've wanted a case that would work for both the laptop and tablet mode. Unfortunately, they really don't seem to exist. The closest I found was the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07D6DPD2N/ref=cm_sw_em_r_mt_dp_U_fKb9Cb3267RRT"&gt;mCover Hard Shell Case for 12.3" Google Pixelbook Chromebook&lt;/a&gt;, but even this wouldn't let you fold it all the way closed for a table mode. At best, you could take the bottom panel off, which required some juggling, and still didn't close right because of the top cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buried within the comments, though, was a gracious 5-star review along with his instructions on how to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/customer-reviews/R3G383RE7SZH5A/ref=cm_cr_dp_d_rvw_ttl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B07D6DPD2N"&gt;modify the case to use in tablet mode&lt;/a&gt;. Brilliant! But for a person like me, I wanted more than a couple photos; I was hoping for some detailed directions on how to do it so I didn't ruin my case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, over a month after getting the case, I broke out my dremels (yes, I have more than one) and started getting to work. First step was to measure, align, and make marks for the modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools Used:
* Dremel Oscillating MultiMax MM30
* Oscillating blade
* Sanding Pad attachment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cuts need to happen in three places: the top cover's back and the two openings required for the bottom cover's buttons. I took some quick photos of the measurement points for reference, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Location&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Measurement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Photo&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Top cover&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.4cm from back&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allows tablet fold to close more completely&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img alt="Top Cover Reference" src="" title="{static}images/2019-06-02-measured-top-edge.jpg"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bottom cover left side, aligned with volume rocker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.2cm - 3.7cm from second clip to back&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Creates opening for volume rocker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img alt="Volume Rocker Reference" src="" title="{static}images/2019-06-02-measured-bottom-button-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bottom cover left side, aligned with power button&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14.2cm-15.6cm from second clip to back&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Creates opening for power button&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img alt="Power Button Reference" src="" title="{static}images/2019-06-02-measured-bottom-button-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you're really &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt; sure that the measurements are right (remember, measure twice, cut once), go ahead and get started cutting those pieces off and out. This was the truly terrifying piece, and I'm not sure I had the perfect tools for this. Plus, I don't have surgeon hands; there's a reason I write &lt;em&gt;software&lt;/em&gt;, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top cover was an easy cut, straight across. I struggled a bit to do a truly straight line, so once the cut was made, I went back with the sanding attachment at the roughest grit and leveled things out. The finer grits were used to soften the plastic and mitigate any chance of scratching the laptop itself. That was a real concern, especially because the clips to keep it from sliding were gone now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The button notches really had me nervous, and i'm certain this was the wrong tool for this part. Fortunately, I'm stubborn. I cut into the side on each marked point, carving a roughly .3cm line with each pass. Once the main lines were cut, I went back in between them and carved out some of the center plastic, which would eventually be removed. Since there wasn't a good way to cut into the side, instead I ended up cutting lots of individual cuts upward, which then gave me smaller slivers of plastic that could be more easily removed. Eventually I was able to come in from the side and cut each of these little pieces off very carefully without doing much damage to the remaining case. These, too, were sanded down to mitigate any sort of scratch-risk to the laptop, however I was unable to buff out the damage I had done from my upward cuts. From above, you can easily see the lines from where the blade went too far in and left permanent grooves on the underside. It almost looks like a shatter-impact from this angle. Fortunately, this will always be underneath or behind what I'm looking at, so it's probably the best place this could've gone wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover Damage near Volume Rocker" src="" title="{static}images/2019-06-02-after-button-notch-damage.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a quick view of the minor gap when folded in tablet mode; while it's annoying, it's worlds better than before the modification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tablet Mode View" src="" title="{static}images/2019-06-02-after-tablet-mode-gap.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a look at the result as a whole, even with my shortcomings aside, it's definitely not perfect; the bottom cover doesn't fit quite right over the keyboard, causing some unpleasant bulging where the cover should lock in more cleanly. In addition, the top panel no longer has clips on all four sides, which means it can just slide off with a relatively minimal amount of force. I accidentally discovered this the first time I picked it up - only slightly terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| The power button opening sits lifted up, not cleanly aligning the clip.|&lt;img alt="Power Button Side Gap" src="" title="{static}images/2019-06-02-after-button-side-gap.jpg"&gt;|
| The volume rocker opening seems flush, but as it moves towards the back, the cover raises up again.|&lt;img alt="Volume Rocker Side Gap" src="" title="{static}images/2019-06-02-after-button-side-gap-2.jpg"&gt;|
|Seen when flipped upside down, in the process of moving to tablet mode.|&lt;img alt="Back View of Top Cover" src="" title="{static}images/2019-06-02-after-back-coverage-gap.jpg"&gt;|&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I had a clue about all of these going in. But this is a $20 case, and I feel like I've gotten some serious added value with less than an hour of work, including the photos I took.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I just have to resist the urge to buy a couple more in complementing colors and swapping them constantly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hobbies"></category><category term="Chromebook"></category></entry><entry><title>Brewing, Baking, and OCD</title><link href="/brewing-baking-and-ocd.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-07-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-07-20:/brewing-baking-and-ocd.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Saturday Brewing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="/late-night-adventures-with-homebrew.html"&gt;Amber After Midnight&lt;/a&gt; batch, once ready to drink, was a knock-out hit. We agreed that the Chinook flavor wasn't necessarily the best profile, though I got some serious lovers of the profile it built. After some consideration of what our Local Homebrew Store had in stock as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Saturday Brewing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="/late-night-adventures-with-homebrew.html"&gt;Amber After Midnight&lt;/a&gt; batch, once ready to drink, was a knock-out hit. We agreed that the Chinook flavor wasn't necessarily the best profile, though I got some serious lovers of the profile it built. After some consideration of what our Local Homebrew Store had in stock as far as hops go, we settled on a Sterling for bittering and Fuggle to get an earthy, nutty, and lightly flowery profile. While it's extremely basic, it's also hitting the core hops to get a good grasp on our groundings so we can build up. Plus, they didn't list the rotational hops on their site and it was around 11pm when we were doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With some guidance from my fellow brewers Jason and Ben, we've also been getting a better understanding of the advantages and disadvantages of using a malt extract. Instead of using an LME Amber, we shifted to doubling the LME Light and the Crystal 40&amp;deg;L both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled with the outcome of our recipe, not to mention how easy the brew day itself is starting to get. The steps are feeling more routine, less scramble to check what's next and more overall comfort in the brew itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we did prove once and for all that I need to stop indoor brewing - the hops aroma filling the house gave me a wicked migraine that knocked me out for about 5 hours solid. Fortunately, sleep cures most migraines, so I was able to bounce back pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does, however, mean that I'll be investing in a turkey fryer and propane setup soon, with the hopes of shiftig to a full boil while I'm at it. (Thus far it's been a partial boil, which I worry has been hurting us on the efficiency of our sugar retention.) I've not yet started shopping for it, but I suspect it's going to be a goodly investment, which means it won't be happening this week, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Baking with the Leftovers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing a brew day, one thing has always bothered me: tons of left over grain. It's called "spent grain," mind you, and it turns out you can use it in baking. I knew this from our first brew, so when we did the Irish Red (years ago and out of a kit! gasp!), a friend and I spent the extra half hour to make up a few batches of bread using the spent grain. But you have to use flour, too, and so it feels awfully wasteful only rescuing about a cup of the spent grain for every loaf of bread made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I stumbled upon a fantastic site called &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/"&gt;Brooklyn Brew Shop&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, the &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/themash/category/spentgrainchef/"&gt;Spent Grain Chef&lt;/a&gt; section is what got my attention; instead of using the wet grain, the author has actually dried and ground the grain into flour and used it as the basis for recipes! I've been excited to give this a try, so today my oven was filled with cookie sheets covered in the spent grain, spread out and running at 170&amp;deg;F for hours on end. It took a few tries to get it mixed up and quit sticking to my utensils, but I think it's finally dried out and ready to be milled down into a flour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to see how it's done, check out the recipe for &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/themash/recipe-spent-grain-flour/"&gt;Spent Grain Flour&lt;/a&gt;. I'm particularly looking forward to making the &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/themash/recipe-spent-grain-peanut-butter-cookies/"&gt;Spent Grain Peanut Butter Cookies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OCD Exposed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me can tell you I have a few ticks. Among them is the need to be orderly in certain things (though sadly not my house as a whole!). At the prompting of a few friends, I rediscovered Perler Beads, those little beads we put on pegboards and ironed as kids for no good reason but got a world of joy from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends have purchased and sorted out several buckets of the beads, and in helping them sort, I was suddenly in OCD heaven. After we subsequently made a few 8-bit video game characters for coasters, I was sold; I had to have my own set. So I hit up my favorite place to buy things online and promptly ordered a bin of 11,000 pieces - and as of today, they've been sorted into two boxes, 30 colors in all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="30 beads organized carefully in rainbow order" src="/articles/images/2014-07-20-beads.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's awful is that now they're all assembled, I'm finding myself at a loss of what to make. The boards for them are particularly huge, so 30x30 beads comes out to something like 6"x6". While that may seem like a lot, imagine a 30x30 pixel image. Our 8-bit adventures led us to make a relatively small Pokeball and Mudkip (a Pokemon for those of you unfamiliar), but even those are large for coasters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My original plan was to mock up the eventual design for my bottle cap collection, getting a nice prototype done. In addition, I'd make some beer-themed coasters. Unfortunately, each of these are larger than my 6"x6" pegboard - meaning that while I can do the prototype, I don't think either of them will be functional as designs for coasters. Perhaps I can go the route of wall decorations or something 3D instead?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hobbies"></category><category term="Homebrew"></category><category term="Baking"></category></entry><entry><title>Spent Grain Cookies</title><link href="/spent-grain-cookies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-07-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-07-20:/spent-grain-cookies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After making my spent grain flour last weekend, I was simply aching to get some baking in with it - not to mention the friends bugging me to make them. I decided on the &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/themash/recipe-spent-grain-peanut-butter-cookies/"&gt;Spent Grain Peanut Butter Cookies&lt;/a&gt;, recipe courtesy of &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/"&gt;Brooklyn Brew Shop&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/themash"&gt;The Mash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon mixing the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After making my spent grain flour last weekend, I was simply aching to get some baking in with it - not to mention the friends bugging me to make them. I decided on the &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/themash/recipe-spent-grain-peanut-butter-cookies/"&gt;Spent Grain Peanut Butter Cookies&lt;/a&gt;, recipe courtesy of &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/"&gt;Brooklyn Brew Shop&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href="http://brooklynbrewshop.com/themash"&gt;The Mash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon mixing the ingredients, I was convinced the batter needed water, or milk, or maybe another egg. The consistency was just all wrong, but I decided to trust the recipe and forged ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Batter" src="" title="{static}images/images/2014-07-28-batter.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success! Now to just make the cookies - this was going decievingly easy. And did I mention this was a double batch? There would be more cookies than we knew what to do with - fortunately I had some social events coming up, not to mention coworkers more than willing to 'help out.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the cookies were all properly aligned on the sheets (and it took two rounds in the oven), I grabbed a fork to do the cross-hatch on the tops. Unfortunately, my silverware is real silver, and has tiny prongs, so I didn't get the gorgeous results like Brooklyn Brew Shop did, but that didn't make them taste any less good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cookies, Pre-Baked" src="" title="{static}images/2014-07-28-cookies-prebaked.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I haven't gotten any good photos of the finished product, as they came out of the oven just as it was time to head to bed, and the next few days I was knocked out by my latest case of Strep Throat. Fortunately I'm now on the up-turn, but not enough so that I want to risk infecting the batch. Once I'm a few days further past, I'll try to get a photo - assuming they aren't all gone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hobbies"></category><category term="Baking"></category></entry><entry><title>Late Night Adventures with Homebrew</title><link href="/late-night-adventures-with-homebrew.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-07-05:/late-night-adventures-with-homebrew.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know I've mentioned I do too much, but this one felt like taking it to an extreme. Since there weren't enough hours in the day, my last brew started at around midnight to help Mike with his first batch. It was a traditional American Amber, based on the recipe …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know I've mentioned I do too much, but this one felt like taking it to an extreme. Since there weren't enough hours in the day, my last brew started at around midnight to help Mike with his first batch. It was a traditional American Amber, based on the recipe from Brew Your Own's &lt;a href="http://byo.com/stories/beer-styles/item/1459-the-10-easiest-beer-styles"&gt;The 10 Easiest Beer Styles&lt;/a&gt;' Outback Amber Ale. Instead of the Crystal 135&amp;deg; L, we picked up ¾ lbs of Special B. The resulting tastiness was a pretty traditional amber, but what really threw me was the grassy flavor at the end; turns out the Chinook hops carried some herbal notes that neither of us were expecting, but it's grown on us both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipe, if you care to check it out, can be found on Brewtoad under the name &lt;a href="https://www.brewtoad.com/recipes/amber-after-midnight"&gt;Amber After Midnight&lt;/a&gt;. I generally keep &lt;a href="https://www.brewtoad.com/users/42827"&gt;all my recipes&lt;/a&gt;. here, so if you're interested, feel free to browse around. I also recommend the site in general; while it's somewhat young feature-wise, I have reason to believe that as it goes forward it will begin to gain some maturity and further adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, the brewing bug has really taken hold of me as of late. The next batch I make is planned to take advantage of some Mosaic hops I picked up during our supply run for the amber. We looked to find a good way to compliment it, and it turns out a brettanomyces yeast can do some very fun, funky things, so I intend to play a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial five-gallon boil (though if I can't get the gear, I might have to do a partial boil) will first use a steep of Crystal 40&amp;deg; L and Victory malts, then a boil with an additional 6.5 lbs of dry malt extract. The Mosaic is going to be late hopped for all 2 oz - 0.5 oz at 30 minutes remaining, 15 minutes remaining, 5 minutes remaining, and then 5 minutes during a flame-out whirlpool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the boil is done, this is where it gets tricky. The 5 gallon batch (whether a full boil or partial topped off with water) will be split off into a 3-gallon carboy and two 1-gallon carboys. The 3-gallon carboy and one of the 1-gallon carboys will get a traditional California Ale yeast (WLP001); the other 1-gallon carboy will get Brettanomyces Bruxellensis Trois (WLP644).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect the 3-gallon batch to fly - probably a 4-8 day fermentation, assuming it's in the basement at about 68&amp;deg; F. We'll bottle that right away, then sit to bottle carbonate for a good 2-3 weeks. Flavor profiles on this should be focused on the Mosaic hops - grapefruit and peach, perhaps, though I've seen reports of a ton of different flavor profiles from this single hop build. Regardless, I'm certain the hops will shine through. Estimated ABV is 5.5% - 6.0%. Estimated yield is 30 12-oz bottles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1-gallon batch with the WLP001 is going to finish equally quickly, and then we'll pitch a non-started pack of the WLP644 for a secondary start. At this point it will get moved to a 70&amp;deg; F to let it get more of the funk aromas. From the preliminary research I've done, this is a mixed-fermentation wherein the brett will overtake the existing yeast and push it far past the point that the WLP001 could take it. I would expect another 2 weeks, finishing between 6.5% AND 7.5% ABV with a yield of approximately 10 bottles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 100% brett batch I expect to start slow and take approximately 2-3 weeks, if not a bit longer, assuming it's sitting at 70&amp;deg; F for the full duration. Flavors on this are likely to be all over the place - fruity for sure, with a more robust funk than the mixed batch. By not taking it too warm and keeping the aeration low for the whole process, the resulting flavors and aromas will be a relatively straightforward fruitiness with a hint of funk, as opposed to the heavy funk levels triggered by higher temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing to keep in mind is that I need to do the starter for the WLP644 early - as much as 10 days early so we've got a good culture to work with. Since it's only a 1-gallon batch, I actually don't expect this to be critical, but always better safe than sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be sure to report back in once the batches are started; I'm anxious to get there, and I'm sure it'll be happening soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hobbies"></category><category term="Homebrew"></category></entry></feed>