<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jen Sparks - Updates</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/updates.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-09-02T12:15:00-05:00</updated><subtitle>A personal playground</subtitle><entry><title>Labor Day Weekend</title><link href="/labor-day-weekend.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-02T12:15:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-02T12:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-09-02:/labor-day-weekend.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's a three-day weekend, and what does that mean? Well, probably getting sick, because the universe is cruel. But that aside, it's actually been quite a relaxing one - we had D&amp;amp;D on Saturday, and shortly before I discovered a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; cool React project called &lt;a href="https://dukeflipchart.github.io/dndspells/"&gt;The Spells of D&amp;amp;D …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's a three-day weekend, and what does that mean? Well, probably getting sick, because the universe is cruel. But that aside, it's actually been quite a relaxing one - we had D&amp;amp;D on Saturday, and shortly before I discovered a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; cool React project called &lt;a href="https://dukeflipchart.github.io/dndspells/"&gt;The Spells of D&amp;amp;D 5e&lt;/a&gt;. It was &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; perfect... and hey, I've never played with React before, so why not give it a spin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backing up a bit - I'm a visualization nerd. Before landing completely in software engineering, I had planned to blend graphic design and programming, two things I'd fallen in love with as a kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am, poking at my news feed on Saturday morning, and this &lt;em&gt;absolutely gorgeous&lt;/em&gt; interactive infographic shows up. What's a girl to do? Share it with the rest of her nerdy friends, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't long before I poked at the source code. From what I could initially see (despite knowing absolutely nothing of node.js or React), &lt;a href="http://github.com/dukeflipchart"&gt;dukeflipchart&lt;/a&gt; had started with a &lt;a href="https://github.com/facebook/create-react-app"&gt;Create React App&lt;/a&gt;, interleaved some specific logic, and integrated the JSON he generated via &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DnD/comments/2qs89e/5e_spell_reference_sheets_are_done/"&gt;u/Zolo49's spell spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;. He's got a pretty solid explanation of the process on the original page; check it out if you're interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I wanted to get my hands dirty, so in my Chromebook fashion, I spun up a Codenvy NodeJS project, forked his project, imported it, and got to poking. The scaffolding for leveling, which felt like a really obvious additional filter to be made available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest changes to make were:
- Add another &lt;code&gt;HighlightLabel&lt;/code&gt; section for the levels
- Add functionality for the new section's &lt;code&gt;onClick&lt;/code&gt; behavior
- Change the &lt;code&gt;getHighlightColors&lt;/code&gt; logic to consider both the casters and the levels
- Update the logic behind &lt;code&gt;hasOpacity&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last one took &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; longer than I'd like to admit. I probably spent a couple hours going in circles, trying to find why logic in one place was behaving so different from another place. While I'm tempted to blame the sick on this, realistically, I just don't know the frameworks being used here, so a lot of the more implicit things (such as these seemingly arbitrary property names) just weren't clicking for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleeping on it seemed to do the trick - when I looked again this morning, tracing line for line, I finally spotted it, and it was such an easy change, it was embarrassing. But it was finished, so all that was left to figure out was publishing to Github-pages, which &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have been easy, except it took me a while more flailing to figure out the right way to get npm to use my personal access token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, though, it's here - &lt;a href="https://jenrsparks.github.io/dndspells/"&gt;The Spells of D&amp;amp;D 5E&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spamming the same nerdy friends, a couple items were flagged for possible improvements:
- Linking to spell descriptions / details
- Additional classes added&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former should be easy, and the latter... well, as &lt;a href="http://github.com/dukeflipchart"&gt;dukeflipchart&lt;/a&gt; said, it's time consuming. But maybe worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Updates"></category><category term="React"></category></entry><entry><title>Memorial Weekend</title><link href="/memorial-weekend.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-27T12:35:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-27T12:35:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-05-27:/memorial-weekend.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a crazy couple of weeks. The kids are officially on summer break, the house has had half a dozen projects to wrap, and work has ramped in an unexpected way. This weekend is supposed to be about rest for me, a couple days to catch up on R …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a crazy couple of weeks. The kids are officially on summer break, the house has had half a dozen projects to wrap, and work has ramped in an unexpected way. This weekend is supposed to be about rest for me, a couple days to catch up on R&amp;amp;R, maybe binge on TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we replaced a screen in a screendoor, mounted two televisions (office and a bedroom), finished assembling the monitor arm for my desk, and spent 5 brutal hours shopping for a loveseat before finding what would work in the space we have. Here we are, two out of three days into the weekend gone, and I'm both physically fried and a little bit mentally blank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got several projects in my head that I want to work on, but right now, I suspect they're going to have to go on the backburner for a bit longer. For the sake of keeping myself honest, though, I'll at least throw them on a list to remind me later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify the Pixelbook case to support tablet mode (see &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/customer-reviews/R3G383RE7SZH5A/ref=cm_cr_dp_d_rvw_ttl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B07D6DPD2N"&gt;customer review comment&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start writing our D&amp;amp;D stories (having just started a new campaign)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Splunk articles here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progress on a work-related side project I'm hoping to opensource (details later if I can)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read any (and all) of the piles of books and comics stacking up:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comics:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://digital.darkhorse.com/series/815/american-gods"&gt;American Gods by Neil Gaiman, P Craig Russell, &amp;amp; Scott Hampton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dccomics.com/comics/cover-2018/cover-1"&gt;Cover by Brian Michael Bendis &amp;amp; David Mack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firefly_(Boom!_Studios_comics)"&gt;Firefly from Boom! Studios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/His_Dark_Materials"&gt;His Dark Materials by Phillip Pullman&lt;/a&gt; (a personal re-read)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norse_Mythology_(book)"&gt;Norse Mythology by Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tor.com/2019/01/16/book-announcements-radicalized-cory-doctorow/"&gt;Radicalized by Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more personal note, I've been considering starting a new fitness routine, but I'm feeling some serious hesitation. The biggest concern is that this is another moneygrab with no real value; I have specific limitations I'm trying to work within, and while this says that it's accommodating to that, all the sample videos and details I've found look like just another exercise program. And since all the cost is up front, if it doesn't work, I'm just out some cash for no real gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My alternative is to just force myself into my own known routines - stretches, cardio, better eating, more consistent sleep schedule. I have the tools, worked hard to get the knowledge to do this over the last couple years. The question is, does the structure of the program add enough value and new information to justify the money? Or is it just another template to provide more of the same stuff I already know? The most annoying part is that I won't know for sure unless I give in and spend the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I'm watching my husband dig in on a 4K HDR playthrough of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horizon_Zero_Dawn"&gt;Horizon: Zero Dawn&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favorite games. The added 5.1.2 surround sound we've installed, plus the 65" TV, has been an absolutely beautiful improvement to a game I adored on my own playthrough. I'm hoping I get to live the journey through his playthrough, rather vicariously, as I read or craft or otherwise ride along, as we often do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Updates"></category><category term="Reading"></category><category term="Home Improvement"></category></entry><entry><title>Reboot 2019 - Jekyll, Codenvy, and CSS</title><link href="/reboot-2019-jekyll-codenvy-and-css.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-27T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-27T12:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-04-27:/reboot-2019-jekyll-codenvy-and-css.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here we are, nearly 2 years later. I've changed jobs (and actually my career as a whole), gotten married, and a dozen other smaller but equally important things. And yet this place has been relative neglected, always a consideration but not something I've put the time into picking back up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here we are, nearly 2 years later. I've changed jobs (and actually my career as a whole), gotten married, and a dozen other smaller but equally important things. And yet this place has been relative neglected, always a consideration but not something I've put the time into picking back up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So first thing's first - the site has been ported into a fork of &lt;a href="https://github.com/poole/hyde"&gt;pool/hyde&lt;/a&gt;, with some customization of the fonts in use. In particular, we've got &lt;a href="https://fonts.google.com/selection?selection.family=Cinzel+Decorative"&gt;Cinzel Decorative&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://fonts.google.com/selection?selection.family=Cinzel"&gt;Cinzel&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://fonts.google.com/selection?selection.family=Raleway"&gt;Raleway&lt;/a&gt;, three beautiful fonts from &lt;a href="https://fonts.google.com"&gt;Google Fonts&lt;/a&gt;. I've additionaly made some shifts to get things up to the latest version of Github.io support -- moving from pygments to rouge in particular mitigated several critical errors keeping the site from running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mind you, a lot of this came about because I've finally gotten a new computer - my 2013 laptop, while still running, just isn't cutting it, and can't be pulled from power anymore. In addition, it doesn't always like to start, or just gives a black screen on startup, which is downright terrifying. So I broke down and got myself a Pixelbook - circa 2017, these guys are still killer, and with the Chrome OS paradigm, everything lives in the cloud. But that means... Where's the runtime environment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've managed to stumble my way into &lt;a href="https://codenvy.io"&gt;Codenvy&lt;/a&gt; with Jekyll, surprising even myself in that I've never really worked with Docker, and it seems like a lot of the initial love for it has faded in the last year. Google searches only got me part of the way, and the rest was a fumble trying to get things working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step one:&lt;/strong&gt; a custom stack to run Jekyll. Turns out, you need something with at least 2.4.0 Ruby, plus jekyll and maybe bundler, depending on the site structure. So my stack definition came out to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p _="%" endhighlight&gt;{% highlight unix %}
FROM eclipse/ruby_rails
RUN sudo gem install jekyll
EXPOSE 4000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step two:&lt;/strong&gt; create the workspace, including specifying your projects from Github. What's great is that in my case, I ended up renaming my original github.io site as &lt;code&gt;sitename_old&lt;/code&gt;, then forking hyde to be &lt;code&gt;sitename&lt;/code&gt;. Fortunately I had the foresight to create my Codenvy account with Github credentials, so that authentication was trivialized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step three:&lt;/strong&gt; get it working! Realisically, that meant running the forked hyde site, getting the right gems installed locally, and resolving the startup errors that happened from progression of the github.io support (specifically moving the highlighter engine from pygments to rouge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step four:&lt;/strong&gt; copy over the posts, resolve the errors, run, and validate. In this case, I got lucky - most of the posts were clean and didn't require any sort of tweaks on their yaml definitions. I'm not thrilled with having the whole darned post showing up instead of snippets, but there's lots of time for tweaks and adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a ton more little additions I've got, both completed and in the works. My favorite so far is &lt;a href="https://github.com/tholman/github-corners"&gt;tholman's github-corners&lt;/a&gt; -- you'll see him up at the top (where you can find the link to the source of this site). It's purely SVG based, and with a couple tweaks, I was able to get it to follow the dynamic theme of the site as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Updates"></category><category term="Chromebook"></category></entry><entry><title>Technology and Personal Ventures</title><link href="/technology-and-personal-ventures.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-06-19:/technology-and-personal-ventures.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, some organizational and internal turmoil reminded me that I am not as settled in my position as I necessarily assume. There is, at the drop of a hat, always the opportunity to move to a different position, or find some new project for which my current toolset is not …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, some organizational and internal turmoil reminded me that I am not as settled in my position as I necessarily assume. There is, at the drop of a hat, always the opportunity to move to a different position, or find some new project for which my current toolset is not the best solution. For all I know, I could be asked to help write control software for an Android based piece of hardware tomorrow, or find myself knee-deep in a full application rewrite next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of being settled, comfortable, one might even say &lt;em&gt;lazy&lt;/em&gt;, I've decided to at least dip a toe in the waters of some programming languages and frameworks that I've not yet encountered. To start, I'll be working my way through the &lt;a href="https://try.kotlinlang.org"&gt;Kotlin Koans&lt;/a&gt;, then perhaps even stretching myself into the &lt;a href="http://adventofcode.com/"&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt; exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more personal note, my family and I have spent an exorbitant amount of time preparing my prior house to put on the market to sell. We've finally reached the point that the finishing touches are being put on things, like final paint touch-ups and getting photos shot for the listing, with an open house planned for next weekend. I'm ever hopeful that we've covered the biggest ticket items and anything that comes up for inspections or the buyer's demands are nominal and can be handled by hiring someone for petty cash. Regardless, the stress and added overhead of selling a house has, and continues, to take its toll on my family. I'm hoping we can shed this burden as soon as possible and get back to being a happy one-house-owned family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With any luck, I'll sneak some time between all the craziness to work on personal projects, learn Kotlin, and keep making myself better. Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Updates"></category></entry><entry><title>Rebooting the System</title><link href="/rebooting-the-system.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-05-25:/rebooting-the-system.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a while, to say the least. Three years, as a matter of fact. I had big plans for this place - projects, a dumping ground for programming exploration and demos and typographical experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've taken the first pass at some cleanup, and I've now got the site running locally …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a while, to say the least. Three years, as a matter of fact. I had big plans for this place - projects, a dumping ground for programming exploration and demos and typographical experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've taken the first pass at some cleanup, and I've now got the site running locally for me in Docker. It's going to be a lot easier to keep up with the maintenance aspect, at least. Writing content, on the other hand, is another challenge, but with any luck, I'll dig up my old project list and get things moving again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Updates"></category></entry><entry><title>Way Too Much</title><link href="/way-too-much.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-06-07:/way-too-much.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It occurs to me; I do way too much. Take this week for instance: I worked extra a few extra hours, brewed after the sun went down, spent some hours rehabbing this site, and even beta testing a new version of a mobile game. That said, I've been considering the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It occurs to me; I do way too much. Take this week for instance: I worked extra a few extra hours, brewed after the sun went down, spent some hours rehabbing this site, and even beta testing a new version of a mobile game. That said, I've been considering the kinds of things I want to talk about here, and it's far more broad than simply programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the things I'll hope to be discussing here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming Theory &amp;amp; Application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beer Brewing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video &amp;amp; Tabletop Games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knitting &amp;amp; Crochet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Random Personal Projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a fair goal for myself is to pick something to post about, every week - hopefully something new I've learned, or some new technique. At the least, I'll go for a progress update on one of the various in-work projects, but I'm going to set a personal expectation of making it more about what I've learned through that progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, I have a family to help move, so I'd better get moving!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Updates"></category></entry><entry><title>Beginning the Journey</title><link href="/beginning-the-journey.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jen Sparks</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-05-11:/beginning-the-journey.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last 6 years I've worked in the I.T. industry, I've often wanted to share the lessons I've learned, but never had an outlet to share these lessons. In an attempt to change this, I'm kicking off this site with the hopes of writing about the types of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last 6 years I've worked in the I.T. industry, I've often wanted to share the lessons I've learned, but never had an outlet to share these lessons. In an attempt to change this, I'm kicking off this site with the hopes of writing about the types of things I encounter, both previously and moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the chance to share what I learn, and with any luck, people can save themselves some time, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~ Jen&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Updates"></category></entry></feed>